# **Dawn Sheedy**

# **Software Engineer**

Seattle, WA ≜ they/them ★ dawnsheedy.com

### **Profile**

I'm a Seattle-based software engineer with several years of experience specializing in full-stack web application development. I have experience across the entire application lifecycle, from planning to production. I take pride in using my life-long passion for technology to work with others to build impactful products.

#### **Skills**

#### **Full-Stack Web Development**

React, Angular, HTML, CSS (SASS), Typescript, Python, Django, NodeJS, Java, SQL, Websockets

#### **Business & Interpersonal**

Agile, Collaboration, Communication, Adaptation, Time Estimation, Planning

# **Development, Planning & Cloud Tools**

Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, GCP, AWS, Azure, Jenkins, Git, Jira, Confluence

### **Hobby & Misc.**

C#, Arduino, Unity, Digital Art

#### **Education**

**Computer Science,** Virginia Commonwealth University

2019 - 2021

# **Professional Experience**

# **Software Development Engineer,** Clearwater Analytics

 Planned and developed a system for hybrid manual & automatic financial document management for clients with billions in investments.

07/2022 - present Seattle, US

09/2021 - 07/2022

Remote (Virginia), US

- Worked with product and design to build functional & beautiful solutions.
- Mentored & trained colleagues on React & Angular
- Pushed for better code quality, documentation, and API design across all apps
- Created a common React component library for company-wide usage

### **Full-Stack Engineer,** *Press Hook*

• Worked as a critical member of an early-stage startup.

- Designed and developed a custom contextual real-time messaging implementation with React and Websockets.
- Implemented CI/CD processes with Github Actions to improve quality and efficiency.
- Led transition to React for front-end components.

# Volunteering

#### **Kinstone**, **LLC** (**Zeldathon**), *Software Developer*

• Worked with a team of volunteers to deliver an event that has raised over \$3 million for charity since 2009.

08/2016 - 02/2022 Remote (Virginia), US

- Worked with internal and 3rd party APIs to implement owned apps.
- Prototyped a real-time captioning utility for greater accessibility.

# Contract Work, Python, Django, Azure, React

05/2022 - 10/2022

• Designed and developed a utility for creating and automatically scoring mental health assessments.

# **Unity Jubeat Rewrite,** *Unity, C#, NodeJS, Python*

- Developed a unity clone of my favorite rhythm game, *Jubeat*, to be played on an iPad Pro.
- An exercise in reverse engineering and learning Unity.

# **DDR Lights,** C++, Arduino, DMX

• Forked the open-source rhythm game, *Stepmania*, to output song data to create automated light shows.

# Virtual Dance Pad, Oculus SDK, Python

• Used the Oculus SDK to track controllers to play *Dance Dance Revolution* without owning a physical dance platform.

#### Forza Telemetry Viewer, React, Websockets, Go

- Created a user interface for displaying current vehicle information from *Forza Horizon* telemetry data.
- Intended for use as a live stream overlay.

## Elite: Dangerous Alexa Skill, Python, AWS

 Utilized Amazon Web Services Lambda functions to create an Alexa skill for controlling aspects of the space flight game Elite: Dangerous

#### Personal Website, React, CSS

• My personal landing page, written in React.